NATHÁLIA XAVIER

26 years old, brazilian, living in Dublin (stamp 2) nathaliazxavier.com | nathaliazxavier@gmail.com | +353 899480157

SUMMARY

I am a digital product designer with over 5 years of experience, having worked as a usability consultant for big companies like CEMIG and Netimóveis (some of the largest energy providers and real estate companies in Brazil). I've also worked in a diversity of projects, from tourism websites to legal applications.

WORK HISTORY

OMEGATEL | 2015 - present, product designer

At Omegatel, I was able to work in product design, graphic design and also to improve my coding skills. I was also responsible for training a web development trainee team. Through a project called Focus, I was able to provide an interface that helped my state's Court of Audits bring standardization, timeliness control of their process, along with useful information through a platform named Dataviva, a project I am also working on. In a new project called Educat, we hope to innovate the way students take exams through CAT - computerized adaptive tests, a statistical methodology that makes shorter exams bring better results, saving time for both the institution and the students through a modern application.

LATITUDE14 | 2012 - 2016, product designer

Latitude14 has both academic and market approaches when working with interaction design consultancy and development. There, I worked with user-centered design techniques such as user research, interviews, personas, questionnaires, benchmarking, usability testing, card sorting, heuristic evaluations, prototyping, UI design and also front-end development for several clients. At Latitude14, I redesigned and increased the sales of social monitoring application Planeta Y, reduced the invoice calls from Bonsucesso Bank through their web platform and created from scratch a graphic service customer service system that increased Novo .Mundo company's productivity

DITO INTERNET | 2011 - 2012, product designer trainee

As part of Dito's team, I learned about startups, digital products, agile, SCRUM, git, metrics and had my first experience working on applications with a large user base. I enjoyed measuring the impacts of design decisions, receiving user feedback and improving the apps as they grew. I really enjoyed working in their multidisciplinary environment. I was able to improve the subscription rate of their main product's homepage and to design a newsletter with their best ever conversion rate at the time.

UEMG'S NIQ AND IMAGE DESIGN CENTER | 2010, editorial design/illustration trainee.

NIQ is an Illustration and Comics group of the University which I attended. We collected the students', ex-students' and teachers' productions and compiled them into zines. I worked collecting their material, organizing it, making layouts and creating comics. At the Image Design Center, I worked on Animation Through Rotoscoping, an extension projects that consisted of making a Rotoscoping animation based on a movie made in the 1970s, so I drew its frames on Adobe Photoshop with a graphic tablet.

INDEPENDENT WORK

Last but not least, I have done freelance work, specially as a front-end developer. I have also worked with visual identity design, concert posters and even packaging design for handmade cosmetics.

EDUCATION

Graduate Degree in Interaction Design | 2013 - 2015 - Pontifical University of Minas Gerais (PUC Minas)

Bachelor's Degree in Graphic Design | 2009 - 2012 - Design School at Minas Gerais State University (UEMG)

To keep up to date with design and technology, I regularly attend to conferences, meetups (such as Rails Girls, ROADSEC and Front In) and take courses to learn new skills.